<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 14:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables at CSSDevConf</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 14:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</guid>
      <description> Here are my slides for Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens which I had the pleasure of giving at CSS Dev Conf.
   Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens  from Stephanie Hobson   Links I mentioned in my talk  Rob Weychert&amp;rsquo;s horror films schedule Designing Effective Data Tables Guidelines for Designing Tables Clear Off the Table MDN&amp;rsquo;s browser compat data in JSON  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Debrief: An Event Apart Austin 2015</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last week, because working at Mozilla is awesome, I got to attend An Event Apart Austin, the conference put on by the A List Apart organization. It&amp;rsquo;s consistently one of the highest quality conferences for front-end/user experience talks. I try to go every other year.
The conference was great and the organizers did a good job making the speakers accessible, sitting them with us at lunch and keeping them around for the mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Debug CSS</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 09:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</guid>
      <description>Some quick notes and links for the talk I gave at WordCamp Vancouver about Debugging CSS.
Edit: You can now watch a recording of Debugging CSS. Spot the three projector failures!
Steps  Is the HTML valid? Is the CSS valid? Is the right CSS being applied?
 Is what you typed being applied? Is other stuff being applied? Is what&amp;rsquo;s being applied right?  Does CSS support what you’re doing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day Two</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 16:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</guid>
      <description>[Edenbee](http://edenbee.com/) Social networking and carbon footprints by Clearleft. [A Dao of Web Design](http://www.alistapart.com/articles/dao) Jeremy Keith says everyone must read this. It talks about giving up pixel perfect control of the display of your websites. [Google social graph API]( http://code.google.com/apis/socialgraph/) Traces XFN and hCard references to connect your different profiles and find out who you are connected to. [SCRUM](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCRUM) Replacement for the waterfall development method. It&#39;s agile. Recommended by Kelly Goto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day One</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 22:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</guid>
      <description>[Bobulate](http://bobulate.com/) Can&#39;t remember why it was mentioned but it is about IA and looks interesting. [Wired](http://www.wired.com/) Apparently half the people in the room read it. Jason used it as an example of how print can be very cool looking but the web is missing that pizzaz for individual articles. [NY Times articles about Trolls](http://www.nytimes.com/2008/08/03/magazine/03trolls-t.html?pagewanted=1&amp;_r=1) Don&#39;t feed the trolls. One of the trials of community managers. [Flickr Colouring Contest](http://flickr.com/groups/flickrcolorcontest/) Making lemonaid out or error messages as part of community management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Directions North 2008</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 20:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north-2008/</guid>
      <description>Just like last year I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post my summary of the conference that I distributed to my department. If I have any regular readers at all, it&amp;rsquo;s probably a little too general to do you any good but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to answer questions:
Web Directions North is an internationally respected conference for web professionals. This year’s conference was a good high level overview of the new trends and technologies online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to check out from WDN08</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Libraries Overview  recommended by Cameron Adams as good comparison of major libraries Twine called Web 3.0 by Boris Mann dotMobi Mobile Web Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide by Brian Fling XHTML Mobile Profile Tutorial apparently if we know XHTML we know XHTML-MP, almost OpenID single sign on for the internet microformats.org/wiki/social-network-portability mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabiltyOAuth.net mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty DiSo Distributed Social networking applications development community kayak good example of potential use of portable data upcoming I have been instructed to get an account getsatisfaction people powered customer service foamee doesn&amp;rsquo;t require account creation, just uses your twitter info cabspotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media links to check out</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-links-to-check-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 02:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-links-to-check-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list consisting of all the websites and books recommended during the course of the conference that interested me enough to warrant writing down for later evaluation (including links to most of the presentations):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media: Day Two</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 02:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Today I got two free books, Jeremy signed Bullet Proof Ajax for me and I snagged an extra Microformats cheat sheet for Brandon. All in all a success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media: Day One</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 10:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-one/</guid>
      <description>One day I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to make the same kind of contribution to the web design world that these speakers have. Trying to find a way to do that is as intimidating as the idea of writing a Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. How does one come up with new ideas?
The speakers have all been excellent so far. I always need a few days to process information though so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say at this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADE/AMTECH Conference</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</guid>
      <description>I was in Winnipeg speaking at the CADE/AMTECH Conference last week. The weather was beautiful and I saw an excellent hockey game in which the Manitoba Moose (the Vancouver Canucks&amp;rsquo; farm team) played spectacularly only to to be knocked out of the AHL playoffs in a very Canucks way (up 2-0 at the end of the first, lost 2-3 in OT).
As part of the Technology Enabled Knowledge (TEK) initiative at BCIT Danny Catt, one of the faculty, was sponsored to take a trip around South America and Antarctica studying local research and responses to sustainability and environmental issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Directions North</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 14:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post my summary of Web Directions North that I distributed to the department a month or so after the conference.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write a more technical and personal review of it but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear to me that if I haven&amp;rsquo;t done it by now, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to get around to doing it :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>