<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014 on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014 on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 11:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Websites Better for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-websites-better-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-websites-better-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a few different versions of my talk floating around now. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited and humbled to hear that people have been making changes to the way the work in response to something I said.
The most detailed (and longest) version of my talk is available to watch on Wordpress TV.
My first slide deck and links to the resources I recommend are part of an earlier blog post.
In the most recent version of my talk I used a demo of a fictional hosting company&amp;rsquo;s server status page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Google Tag Manager</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-tag-manager-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 22:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-tag-manager-intro/</guid>
      <description>Google Tag Manager (GTM) is still pretty new as I write this. Stuff is still changing so I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to focus on techniques rather than step by step instructions (but I have some of those too).
What is GTM You include a code snippet from GTM on your site which, among other things, includes a file. Then you use the GTM interface to configure what goes in that file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility with CSS: Making Websites Better for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-with-css-making-websites-better-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-with-css-making-websites-better-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description> Last night I spoke at the Style &amp;amp; Class Meet-up about Accessibility and CSS. Posting the slides here for posterity:
   Accessibility with CSS: Making Websites Better for Everyone  from Stephanie Hobson   Resources  Intro to Accessibility WCAG Validator Intro to ARIA :Focus and keyboard accessibility High contrast CSS Sprites Bullet Proof Accessible Icon Fonts The Offscreen Class Floating Form Labels Javascript fix for Skip Links  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Matter of Semantics</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/a-matter-of-semantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 20:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/a-matter-of-semantics/</guid>
      <description>Adapted from a blog post on Web Services&amp;rsquo; blog at BCIT, the audience was our content community: people who contribute content using the CMS, with little to no technical experience.
Once, as part of a “getting to know you” activity at summer camp, I played a game where I was given a drawing and another camper was given a paper and pencil. Without her seeing the drawing, and without me seeing her paper, I had to try to get her to draw what I could see.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>