<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016 on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016 on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 11:43:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping More Tables</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-more-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 11:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-more-tables/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I gave my talk on displaying data tables on small screens at Cascadia Fest. Which is a super awesome 3 days conference in the Pacific North West focusing on CSS and JavaScript (Browser and Server side!)
The video of my talk has been posted:   And my slides are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics, Privacy, and Event Tracking</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-analytics-privacy-and-event-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-analytics-privacy-and-event-tracking/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on the Mozilla Hacks blog.
Many of us use Google Analytics (GA) or similar third-party services to keep track of how people interact with our websites; telling us things like when people visit and what they click. This data can help us make important decisions, such as when to schedule maintenance or if a feature can be removed.
Because these services are installed on multiple websites these third-parties can collect a lot of information about people as they move around the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables/</guid>
      <description>I was very pleased to be invited back to Style and Class to give a talk about making data tables responsive. Style and Class is a great Vancouver meet-up I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend enough.
Here are my slides, though the video and animated gifs don&amp;rsquo;t play :(
   Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens  from Stephanie Hobson   And the links I encouraged everyone to check out:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>