<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017 on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:19:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How we rebuilt the viewsourceconf.org website</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-we-rebuilt-the-viewsourceconf-org-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-we-rebuilt-the-viewsourceconf-org-website/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on Mozilla’s Hacks Blog.
As a front-end developer at Mozilla, I end up working on big sites that have been around for a long time. There are a lot of interesting challenges when working with legacy code at a large scale, but rebuilding from scratch usually isn’t an option.
The View Source Conference website, on the other hand, is a small site. So when we decided to move away from WordPress, we had the chance to start fresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables at CSSDevConf</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 14:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</guid>
      <description> Here are my slides for Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens which I had the pleasure of giving at CSS Dev Conf.
   Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens  from Stephanie Hobson   Links I mentioned in my talk  Rob Weychert&amp;rsquo;s horror films schedule Designing Effective Data Tables Guidelines for Designing Tables Clear Off the Table MDN&amp;rsquo;s browser compat data in JSON  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MDN Redesign “Behind the Scenes”</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/the-mdn-redesign-behind-the-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 19:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/the-mdn-redesign-behind-the-scenes/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s Hacks Blog.
Kuma, the code that produces the MDN site, is a weird mix of the old and the new. MDN turned ten in 2015 and there’s still code and content around from those very first days. When I sat down to start coding the current redesign, the first thing I did was remove the last few traces of the last redesign. In contrast, we have a cutting-edge audience: 92% of our users have a browser with CSS grid support!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>