<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Friends on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/friends/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Friends on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 21:03:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/friends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility Problem with Gilder/Levin Image Replacement Method</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 21:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</guid>
      <description>I have a friend who lives his life in low contrast. He is frequently the inspiration I need to go the extra mile and find an accessible solution to a programing quandary. A few weeks ago I had the good fortune to get to visit him and we cruised around the internet while drinking Rusty Nails so I could walk in his shoes for a bit.
His computer is set up to use one of Windows XP&amp;rsquo;s high contrast colour schemes and he also makes use of IE&amp;rsquo;s ability to override a website&amp;rsquo;s CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We made the cut!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/we-made-the-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 11:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/we-made-the-cut/</guid>
      <description>One of the videos we made the other day made the cut into the final Gmail behind the scenes video. Alistair&amp;rsquo;s fancy editing shows the three of us morphing between chin up bars with 1:37 left to go.
A second video of ours was chosen as a featured clip. If you got to the page with the final Gmail behind the scenes video and scroll down to the map, our multi monitor video appears if you click the Vancouver icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 seconds of my 15 minutes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/10-seconds-of-my-15-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/10-seconds-of-my-15-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Google is having this contesty thingy. Which basically requires you to make 10 second (or less) videos of how gMail gets around the world. The idea is for people to get the &amp;ldquo;Mvelope&amp;rdquo; from the left to the right side of the screen.
Yesterday after work Alistair filmed videos with my and Kenzie&amp;rsquo;s help, three are up on youtube now:
 From computer to computer Chin up bars with fancy editing Gmail for lunch  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>