<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cade on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/cade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cade on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/cade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CADE/AMTECH Conference</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</guid>
      <description>I was in Winnipeg speaking at the CADE/AMTECH Conference last week. The weather was beautiful and I saw an excellent hockey game in which the Manitoba Moose (the Vancouver Canucks&amp;rsquo; farm team) played spectacularly only to to be knocked out of the AHL playoffs in a very Canucks way (up 2-0 at the end of the first, lost 2-3 in OT).
As part of the Technology Enabled Knowledge (TEK) initiative at BCIT Danny Catt, one of the faculty, was sponsored to take a trip around South America and Antarctica studying local research and responses to sustainability and environmental issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m presenting at a conference!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 14:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</guid>
      <description>One of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on at BCIT is Catt-Trax2. The website is for Danny Catt who is traveling through South America and Antarctica exploring conservation and sustainability issues and talking to the people in those regions working with those issues daily. He&amp;rsquo;s taking photos, video, and sound clips of this journey and blogging about his experiences. I helped architect the website and did some design and implementation work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>