<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ux on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/ux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ux on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 15:15:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookstore wins a hubbie</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</guid>
      <description>Almost a year ago now the BCIT Bookstore let Web Services know that the e-commerce application they used to manage their online sales was upgrading and asked if we&amp;rsquo;d like to help skin the new site. The department was pretty busy at the time and my manager said we didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to help out but put them in contact with me so I could direct them to the style guide and technical guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, wait, I wasn&#39;t done reading that!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/no-wait-i-wasnt-done-reading-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2007 00:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/no-wait-i-wasnt-done-reading-that/</guid>
      <description>When I went on vacation a few weeks ago I got a little behind on my RSS feeds. I&amp;rsquo;d manage to whittle it down from almost 200 unread articles to about 40 over the course of the month, while keeping up with all the new articles, and I was feeling pretty good about it when I went to switch my view from new items to all items and hit &amp;ldquo;mark all as read&amp;rdquo; instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming form guidelines</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/forming-form-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 16:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/forming-form-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Who knew web design could be so&amp;hellip; academic?
Since I got back from @media I&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work on a set of guidelines which ideally will one day guide the interaction and styling of all forms on the myriad of BCIT web applications though right now will only be applied to anything in the &amp;lsquo;public web&amp;rsquo; look and feel. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve done this much research since I finished university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Directions North</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/web-directions-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 14:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/web-directions-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post my summary of Web Directions North that I distributed to the department a month or so after the conference.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write a more technical and personal review of it but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear to me that if I haven&amp;rsquo;t done it by now, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to get around to doing it :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>