<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dull April Fool&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</guid>
      <description>There was a rash of black and white April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day sites this year. We weren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones to do it but I think we did it best, if I do say so myself. There were three parts to our little switch and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been the same without any of them:
 Desaturating the colours in the style sheet. Desaturating every image on the site, that&amp;rsquo;s right, all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADE/AMTECH Conference</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</guid>
      <description>I was in Winnipeg speaking at the CADE/AMTECH Conference last week. The weather was beautiful and I saw an excellent hockey game in which the Manitoba Moose (the Vancouver Canucks&amp;rsquo; farm team) played spectacularly only to to be knocked out of the AHL playoffs in a very Canucks way (up 2-0 at the end of the first, lost 2-3 in OT).
As part of the Technology Enabled Knowledge (TEK) initiative at BCIT Danny Catt, one of the faculty, was sponsored to take a trip around South America and Antarctica studying local research and responses to sustainability and environmental issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working hard?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/working-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 17:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/working-hard/</guid>
      <description>Or hardly working?
When the network goes down the whole department starts acting like school kids when the power goes out. We sit around waiting for the power to come back on or the teachers to tell us to go home and the longer it&amp;rsquo;s out the more trouble we contemplate causing ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styling Our Style Sheets</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/styling-our-style-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 13:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/styling-our-style-sheets/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to seriously redo some of the HTML and CSS behind the BCIT site since I came on board here almost a year ago.
Well, I get my wish. We&amp;rsquo;re going to take some baby steps towards semantic HTML and CSS (POSH if you like) and despite my aversion to being in charge, I&amp;rsquo;m leading the project.
As a first step I&amp;rsquo;m trying to write a CSS coding style guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Directions North</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/web-directions-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 14:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/web-directions-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post my summary of Web Directions North that I distributed to the department a month or so after the conference.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write a more technical and personal review of it but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear to me that if I haven&amp;rsquo;t done it by now, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to get around to doing it :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s keeping me busy?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/whats-keeping-me-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 12:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/whats-keeping-me-busy/</guid>
      <description>Well, outside of my day job I&amp;rsquo;m:
 making my Mum a website moving hosting servers for digitalphoenix.ca learning cgi so I can create an auto generated thank you message for HOPE&amp;rsquo;s donors taking Mandarin (what was I thinking?)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>