<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2008 on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2008 on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 16:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I&#39;d like to see Google Reader do</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/stuff-id-like-to-see-google-reader-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 16:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/stuff-id-like-to-see-google-reader-do/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could filter my feeds like I do my email, marking the news items in my web comic feeds as read automatically and blocking (deleting? marking as read?) feeds originating at certain URLs (some of my friends have different&amp;hellip; taste than I do&amp;hellip; repeatedly).
I also wish I could share my feeds with different audiences in mind. Right now what I share is pretty bland because my clients, friends, and family all see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day Two</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 16:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Edenbee Social networking and carbon footprints by Clearleft. A Dao of Web Design Jeremy Keith says everyone must read this. It talks about giving up pixel perfect control of the display of your websites. Google social graph API Traces XFN and hCard references to connect your different profiles and find out who you are connected to. SCRUM Replacement for the waterfall development method. It&amp;rsquo;s agile. Recommended by Kelly Goto. Trulia Snapshot Data visualization by Stamen - using real estate in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day One</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 22:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Bobulate Can&amp;rsquo;t remember why it was mentioned but it is about IA and looks interesting. Wired Apparently half the people in the room read it. Jason used it as an example of how print can be very cool looking but the web is missing that pizzaz for individual articles. NY Times articles about Trolls Don&amp;rsquo;t feed the trolls. One of the trials of community managers. Flickr Colouring Contest Making lemonaid out or error messages as part of community management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site for my favorite client</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/new-site-for-my-favorite-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/new-site-for-my-favorite-client/</guid>
      <description>Just updated the look of Mum&amp;rsquo;s campaign website: Barb Hobson | A Strong Persistent Voice for Coquitlam-Maillardville. I changed everything without altering one line of HTML, man do I love CSS (IE6, I still hate you).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility Problem with Gilder/Levin Image Replacement Method</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 21:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</guid>
      <description>I have a friend who lives his life in low contrast. He is frequently the inspiration I need to go the extra mile and find an accessible solution to a programing quandary. A few weeks ago I had the good fortune to get to visit him and we cruised around the internet while drinking Rusty Nails so I could walk in his shoes for a bit.
His computer is set up to use one of Windows XP&amp;rsquo;s high contrast colour schemes and he also makes use of IE&amp;rsquo;s ability to override a website&amp;rsquo;s CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight random things</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/eight-random-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 04:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/eight-random-things/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of Jeremy Keith&amp;rsquo;s post, here&amp;rsquo;s 8 random things I see about me:
 Black queen carved like Raven. Small brass Buddha. Wind up penguin. iPhone. Microformats pocket cheat sheet. Salt. 8.5 x 11 print out of the gMail &amp;ldquo;mvelope&amp;rdquo;. Label from a Christmas present: &amp;ldquo;To Steph Love, Joel, Jim &amp;amp; Mrs. A.&amp;rdquo;  You&amp;rsquo;re it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookstore wins a hubbie</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</guid>
      <description>Almost a year ago now the BCIT Bookstore let Web Services know that the e-commerce application they used to manage their online sales was upgrading and asked if we&amp;rsquo;d like to help skin the new site. The department was pretty busy at the time and my manager said we didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to help out but put them in contact with me so I could direct them to the style guide and technical guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two steps forward, one step back</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/two-steps-forward-one-step-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 15:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/two-steps-forward-one-step-back/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday I was a guest speaker at Mrs.A&amp;rsquo;s gifted class. She&amp;rsquo;s teaching a group of 9-12 year olds web design and asked if I&amp;rsquo;d come in an talk for an afternoon.
So I spent 30 minutes talking to them about the basics of user centred design and how the internet works. Then I helped them trouble shoot their table based layouts and font tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Directions North 2008</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 20:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/web-directions-north-2008/</guid>
      <description>Just like last year I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post my summary of the conference that I distributed to my department. If I have any regular readers at all, it&amp;rsquo;s probably a little too general to do you any good but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to answer questions:
Web Directions North is an internationally respected conference for web professionals. This year’s conference was a good high level overview of the new trends and technologies online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping up</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/keeping-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 20:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/keeping-up/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;From your 77 subscriptions, over the last 30 days you read 809 items&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
 No wonder I don&amp;rsquo;t read any books any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally figured out what my problem is</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/finally-figure-out-what-my-problem-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 11:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/finally-figure-out-what-my-problem-is/</guid>
      <description>I read John Resig&amp;rsquo;s article Sub-Pixel Problems in CSS a few days ago and found it to very useful information.
And then today I had an &amp;ldquo;ah-ha&amp;rsquo; moment - this this is why I hate coding flexible horizontal navigation menus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Launches Social Graph API</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-launches-social-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-launches-social-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>There were several speakers at WDN who spoke about open social networks, portability and consolidating friend information across applications. I found the talks interesting and then, while we were still at the conference, Google announced a Social Graph API aiming to do just what we&amp;rsquo;d been talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to check out from WDN08</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Libraries Overview recommended by Cameron Adams as good comparison of major libraries Twine called Web 3.0 by Boris Mann dotMobi Mobile Web Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide by Brian Fling XHTML Mobile Profile Tutorial apparently if we know XHTML we know XHTML-MP, almost OpenID single sign on for the internet microformats.org/wiki/social-network-portability mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty OAuth.net mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty DiSo Distributed Social networking applications development community kayak good example of potential use of portable data upcoming I have been instructed to get an account getsatisfaction people powered customer service foamee doesn&amp;rsquo;t require account creation, just uses your twitter info cabspotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing table based layouts</title>
      <link>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/missing-table-based-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 18:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/missing-table-based-layouts/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s only one time where I ever really miss table based layouts: when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make a flexible horizontal navigation bar with centred links. Like this or this](http://louisgervais.com) website I made for a Vancouver gourmet catering company. chews on keyboard with frustration</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>