<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentation on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentation on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/flipping-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/flipping-tables/</guid>
      <description>I was very pleased to be invited back to Style and Class to give a talk about making data tables responsive. Style and Class is a great Vancouver meet-up I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend enough.
Here are my slides, though the video and animated gifs don&amp;rsquo;t play :(
 ** [Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens](//www.slideshare.net/stephaniehobson/flipping-tables-displaying-data-on-small-screens &#34;Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens&#34;) ** from **[Stephanie Hobson](//www.slideshare.net/stephaniehobson)**  Download the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Debug CSS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/how-to-debug-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 09:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/how-to-debug-css/</guid>
      <description>Some quick notes and links for the talk I gave at WordCamp Vancouver about Debugging CSS.
Edit: You can now watch a recording of Debugging CSS. Spot the three projector failures!
Steps  Is the HTML valid? Is the CSS valid? Is the right CSS being applied?
 Is what you typed being applied? Is other stuff being applied? Is what&amp;rsquo;s being applied right?  Does CSS support what you’re doing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Forms OF DOOM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/html5-forms-of-doom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 16:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/html5-forms-of-doom/</guid>
      <description>I spoke at an HTML5 Code Camp the other day on HTML5 forms because HTML5 forms are cool! They&amp;rsquo;re so cool you can use most of them today anywhere you have a text field to increase functionality for your users!
 ** [HTML5 Forms OF DOOM](https://www.slideshare.net/stephaniehobson/html5-forms-of-doom &#34;HTML5 Forms OF DOOM&#34;) ** from **[stephaniehobson](http://www.slideshare.net/stephaniehobson)**  Download the slides.
Sample form.
Finished form (no peeking).
Resources Basic Introductions
 Dive Into HTML5: A Form of Madness Have a Field Day with HTML5 Forms Making Forms Fabulous with HTML5 Forward Thinking Form Validation CSS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADE/AMTECH Conference</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</guid>
      <description>I was in Winnipeg speaking at the CADE/AMTECH Conference last week. The weather was beautiful and I saw an excellent hockey game in which the Manitoba Moose (the Vancouver Canucks&amp;rsquo; farm team) played spectacularly only to to be knocked out of the AHL playoffs in a very Canucks way (up 2-0 at the end of the first, lost 2-3 in OT).
As part of the Technology Enabled Knowledge (TEK) initiative at BCIT Danny Catt, one of the faculty, was sponsored to take a trip around South America and Antarctica studying local research and responses to sustainability and environmental issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m presenting at a conference!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 14:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</guid>
      <description>One of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on at BCIT is Catt-Trax2. The website is for Danny Catt who is traveling through South America and Antarctica exploring conservation and sustainability issues and talking to the people in those regions working with those issues daily. He&amp;rsquo;s taking photos, video, and sound clips of this journey and blogging about his experiences. I helped architect the website and did some design and implementation work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>