<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2015 on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2015 on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:31:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/year/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Debrief: An Event Apart Austin 2015</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last week, because working at Mozilla is awesome, I got to attend An Event Apart Austin, the conference put on by the A List Apart organization. It&amp;rsquo;s consistently one of the highest quality conferences for front-end/user experience talks. I try to go every other year.
The conference was great and the organizers did a good job making the speakers accessible, sitting them with us at lunch and keeping them around for the mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Debug CSS</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 09:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</guid>
      <description>Some quick notes and links for the talk I gave at WordCamp Vancouver about Debugging CSS.
Edit: You can now watch a recording of Debugging CSS. Spot the three projector failures!
  Steps  Is the HTML valid? Is the CSS valid? Is the right CSS being applied?  Is what you typed being applied? Is other stuff being applied? Is what&amp;rsquo;s being applied right?  Does CSS support what you’re doing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First Is Performance First</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/mobile-first-is-performance-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 22:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/mobile-first-is-performance-first/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I spoke at Vancouver Web Performance Meetup and I promised to share my slides so here they are:
   Mobile First Is Performance First  from Stephanie Hobson   If what you&amp;rsquo;re really after are the links, let me save you a bit of time:
 Patrick Hamann - Building theguardian.com (slides) and Breaking News at 1000ms (video) Paul Irish - Delivering the Goods in under 1000ms (video) Scott Jehl - Responsible Responsive Design (book) Ilya Grigorik - High Performance Browser Networking” (book - free online!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>