<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fun on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fun on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Stranger</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/perfect-stranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/perfect-stranger/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is an amazing tool to catch a glimpse of the collective consciousness. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it during the Olympics and I&amp;rsquo;ve been apart of it at conferences like An Event Apart. Jeremy Keith once said that Twitter was the closest he&amp;rsquo;d ever come to feeling as though he&amp;rsquo;s jacked into the Matrix.
Most of us use Twitter to keep in touch with people we know and keep up with things we care about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dull April Fool&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</guid>
      <description>There was a rash of black and white April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day sites this year. We weren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones to do it but I think we did it best, if I do say so myself. There were three parts to our little switch and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been the same without any of them:
 Desaturating the colours in the style sheet. Desaturating every image on the site, that&amp;rsquo;s right, all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight random things</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/eight-random-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 04:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/eight-random-things/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of Jeremy Keith&amp;rsquo;s post, here&amp;rsquo;s 8 random things I see about me:
 Black queen carved like Raven. Small brass Buddha. Wind up penguin. iPhone. Microformats pocket cheat sheet. Salt. 8.5 x 11 print out of the gMail &amp;ldquo;mvelope&amp;rdquo;. Label from a Christmas present: &amp;ldquo;To Steph Love, Joel, Jim &amp;amp; Mrs. A.&amp;rdquo;  You&amp;rsquo;re it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to check out from WDN08</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Libraries Overview  recommended by Cameron Adams as good comparison of major libraries Twine called Web 3.0 by Boris Mann dotMobi Mobile Web Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide by Brian Fling XHTML Mobile Profile Tutorial apparently if we know XHTML we know XHTML-MP, almost OpenID single sign on for the internet microformats.org/wiki/social-network-portability mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabiltyOAuth.net mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty DiSo Distributed Social networking applications development community kayak good example of potential use of portable data upcoming I have been instructed to get an account getsatisfaction people powered customer service foamee doesn&amp;rsquo;t require account creation, just uses your twitter info cabspotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We made the cut!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/we-made-the-cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 11:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/we-made-the-cut/</guid>
      <description>One of the videos we made the other day made the cut into the final Gmail behind the scenes video. Alistair&amp;rsquo;s fancy editing shows the three of us morphing between chin up bars with 1:37 left to go.
A second video of ours was chosen as a featured clip. If you got to the page with the final Gmail behind the scenes video and scroll down to the map, our multi monitor video appears if you click the Vancouver icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 seconds of my 15 minutes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/10-seconds-of-my-15-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 15:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/10-seconds-of-my-15-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Google is having this contesty thingy. Which basically requires you to make 10 second (or less) videos of how gMail gets around the world. The idea is for people to get the &amp;ldquo;Mvelope&amp;rdquo; from the left to the right side of the screen.
Yesterday after work Alistair filmed videos with my and Kenzie&amp;rsquo;s help, three are up on youtube now:
 From computer to computer Chin up bars with fancy editing Gmail for lunch  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the switch</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/making-the-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 23:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/making-the-switch/</guid>
      <description>Macs have always struck me as more of a religion than an operating system. A family friend and I have a long history of a friendly Mac vs Windows rivalry. He&amp;rsquo;s the Mac evangelist and I was, well, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a Windows evangelist but I guess I played the part of a disbeliever.
At some point in 2004 he finally won the argument and I promised my next computer would be a Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media: Day One</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/media-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 10:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/media-day-one/</guid>
      <description>One day I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to make the same kind of contribution to the web design world that these speakers have. Trying to find a way to do that is as intimidating as the idea of writing a Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. How does one come up with new ideas?
The speakers have all been excellent so far. I always need a few days to process information though so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say at this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working hard?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/working-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 17:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/working-hard/</guid>
      <description>Or hardly working?
When the network goes down the whole department starts acting like school kids when the power goes out. We sit around waiting for the power to come back on or the teachers to tell us to go home and the longer it&amp;rsquo;s out the more trouble we contemplate causing ;)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>