<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webdesign on Stephanie Hobson</title>
    <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/tags/webdesign/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webdesign on Stephanie Hobson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:19:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stephaniehobson.ca/tags/webdesign/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How we rebuilt the viewsourceconf.org website</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-we-rebuilt-the-viewsourceconf-org-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-we-rebuilt-the-viewsourceconf-org-website/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on Mozilla’s Hacks Blog.
As a front-end developer at Mozilla, I end up working on big sites that have been around for a long time. There are a lot of interesting challenges when working with legacy code at a large scale, but rebuilding from scratch usually isn’t an option.
The View Source Conference website, on the other hand, is a small site. So when we decided to move away from WordPress, we had the chance to start fresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables at CSSDevConf</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 14:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables-at-cssdevconf/</guid>
      <description> Here are my slides for Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens which I had the pleasure of giving at CSS Dev Conf.
   Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens  from Stephanie Hobson   Links I mentioned in my talk  Rob Weychert&amp;rsquo;s horror films schedule Designing Effective Data Tables Guidelines for Designing Tables Clear Off the Table MDN&amp;rsquo;s browser compat data in JSON  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping More Tables</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-more-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 11:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-more-tables/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I gave my talk on displaying data tables on small screens at Cascadia Fest. Which is a super awesome 3 days conference in the Pacific North West focusing on CSS and JavaScript (Browser and Server side!)
The video of my talk has been posted:   And my slides are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics, Privacy, and Event Tracking</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-analytics-privacy-and-event-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-analytics-privacy-and-event-tracking/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on the Mozilla Hacks blog.
Many of us use Google Analytics (GA) or similar third-party services to keep track of how people interact with our websites; telling us things like when people visit and what they click. This data can help us make important decisions, such as when to schedule maintenance or if a feature can be removed.
Because these services are installed on multiple websites these third-parties can collect a lot of information about people as they move around the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flipping Tables</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/flipping-tables/</guid>
      <description>I was very pleased to be invited back to Style and Class to give a talk about making data tables responsive. Style and Class is a great Vancouver meet-up I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend enough.
Here are my slides, though the video and animated gifs don&amp;rsquo;t play :(
   Flipping Tables: Displaying Data on Small Screens  from Stephanie Hobson   And the links I encouraged everyone to check out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Debrief: An Event Apart Austin 2015</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/conference-debrief-an-event-apart-austin-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last week, because working at Mozilla is awesome, I got to attend An Event Apart Austin, the conference put on by the A List Apart organization. It&amp;rsquo;s consistently one of the highest quality conferences for front-end/user experience talks. I try to go every other year.
The conference was great and the organizers did a good job making the speakers accessible, sitting them with us at lunch and keeping them around for the mixer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Debug CSS</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 09:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/how-to-debug-css/</guid>
      <description>Some quick notes and links for the talk I gave at WordCamp Vancouver about Debugging CSS.
Edit: You can now watch a recording of Debugging CSS. Spot the three projector failures!
Steps  Is the HTML valid? Is the CSS valid? Is the right CSS being applied?
 Is what you typed being applied? Is other stuff being applied? Is what&amp;rsquo;s being applied right?  Does CSS support what you’re doing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First Is Performance First</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/mobile-first-is-performance-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 22:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/mobile-first-is-performance-first/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I spoke at Vancouver Web Performance Meetup and I promised to share my slides so here they are:
   Mobile First Is Performance First  from Stephanie Hobson   If what you&amp;rsquo;re really after are the links, let me save you a bit of time:
 Patrick Hamann - Building theguardian.com (slides) and Breaking News at 1000ms (video) Paul Irish - Delivering the Goods in under 1000ms (video) Scott Jehl - Responsible Responsive Design (book) Ilya Grigorik - High Performance Browser Networking” (book - free online!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Websites Better for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-websites-better-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-websites-better-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a few different versions of my talk floating around now. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited and humbled to hear that people have been making changes to the way the work in response to something I said.
The most detailed (and longest) version of my talk is available to watch on Wordpress TV.
My first slide deck and links to the resources I recommend are part of an earlier blog post.
In the most recent version of my talk I used a demo of a fictional hosting company&amp;rsquo;s server status page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility with CSS: Making Websites Better for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-with-css-making-websites-better-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 17:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-with-css-making-websites-better-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description> Last night I spoke at the Style &amp;amp; Class Meet-up about Accessibility and CSS. Posting the slides here for posterity:
   Accessibility with CSS: Making Websites Better for Everyone  from Stephanie Hobson   Resources  Intro to Accessibility WCAG Validator Intro to ARIA :Focus and keyboard accessibility High contrast CSS Sprites Bullet Proof Accessible Icon Fonts The Offscreen Class Floating Form Labels Javascript fix for Skip Links  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Matter of Semantics</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/a-matter-of-semantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 20:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/a-matter-of-semantics/</guid>
      <description>Adapted from a blog post on Web Services&amp;rsquo; blog at BCIT, the audience was our content community: people who contribute content using the CMS, with little to no technical experience.
Once, as part of a “getting to know you” activity at summer camp, I played a game where I was given a drawing and another camper was given a paper and pencil. Without her seeing the drawing, and without me seeing her paper, I had to try to get her to draw what I could see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Forms OF DOOM</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/html5-forms-of-doom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 16:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/html5-forms-of-doom/</guid>
      <description>I spoke at an HTML5 Code Camp the other day on HTML5 forms because HTML5 forms are cool! They&amp;rsquo;re so cool you can use most of them today anywhere you have a text field to increase functionality for your users!
   HTML5 Forms OF DOOM  from Stephanie Hobson   Sample form.
Finished form (no peeking).
Resources Basic Introductions
 Dive Into HTML5: A Form of Madness Have a Field Day with HTML5 Forms Making Forms Fabulous with HTML5 Forward Thinking Form Validation  CSS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leave</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 23:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/leave/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a one year leave of absence from my job at BCIT beginning June 1st, 2012.
Right now it kind of feels like I&amp;rsquo;m doing this because I&amp;rsquo;m crazy.
I&amp;rsquo;m really doing it because there&amp;rsquo;s stuff I want to do.
I want to build something cool. I want to learn something new. I want to live in London. I want to live in San Francisco. I want to hang out with the dear friends who live in each city who I have been apart from for way to long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Loading Spinner</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css-loading-spinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css-loading-spinner/</guid>
      <description>I needed a loading spinner for a side project the other day but I was too lazy to steal someone else&amp;rsquo;s off the internet or try to re-learn making an animated GIF so I just coded my own in CSS (CSS is my hammer).
On the bright side it works on any background colour and is a little transparent which is neat. And it&amp;rsquo;s way faster to adjust the colour scheme than an image file would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dull April Fool&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 18:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/dull-april-fools-day/</guid>
      <description>There was a rash of black and white April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day sites this year. We weren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones to do it but I think we did it best, if I do say so myself. There were three parts to our little switch and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been the same without any of them:
 Desaturating the colours in the style sheet. Desaturating every image on the site, that&amp;rsquo;s right, all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FireFox&#39;s buttons are wider than IE or Chrome/Safari&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/firefoxs-buttons-wider-than-ie-or-chrome-safari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 14:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/firefoxs-buttons-wider-than-ie-or-chrome-safari/</guid>
      <description>I hate form styling on the best of days. This is a good example of why:
Firefox&amp;rsquo;s buttons are wider than IE&amp;rsquo;s or Webkit&amp;rsquo;s. Why? This little gem in the browser&amp;rsquo;s style sheets:
button::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;reset&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;file&amp;quot;] &amp;gt; input[type=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner { padding: 0px 2px 0px 2px; }  That&amp;rsquo;s right, it&amp;rsquo;s 4px wider. Thank you FireFox.
Fortunately, we can fix it!
button::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;reset&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;submit&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner, input[type=&amp;quot;file&amp;quot;] &amp;gt; input[type=&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;]::-moz-focus-inner { padding: 0px; }  That was easy :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullets aligned to the top of the text</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bullets-alligned-top-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 12:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bullets-alligned-top-text/</guid>
      <description>Know how IE and FF display list-style-image bullets at two different heights and it drives us all nuts?
Did you know it was possible to use vertical-align on any inline element? Did you know that first-line is an inline element?
If you&amp;rsquo;re working on displaying the bullets at the same height, this might be the fix for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS3 only cover flow</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css3-only-cover-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 22:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css3-only-cover-flow/</guid>
      <description>Nothing teaches me how to do something like a project and I was trying to learn CSS3 so I tried to make a CSS only cover flow.
Some of it works in FireFox but all the cool stuff works best in webkit: here&amp;rsquo;s as far as I got.
Have fun with it :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining your CSS helps maintain your site</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/maintaining-css-help-maintain-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 12:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/maintaining-css-help-maintain-site/</guid>
      <description>Rather than doing one giant redesign and launch, at BCIT, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing small updates for a while now.
Take our footer for example, I got to update all of them using the CSS a few times and then we decided we wanted to mix up the HTML. Templates and applications were updated with the new code in phases. There were a few different ways the CSS for this could have been managed but I chose to have the old code co-exist with the new in the same style sheet and differentiated the two with IDs (let&amp;rsquo;s say I called them #footer and #fatfooter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperfect Pitch</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/im-perfect-pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 13:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/im-perfect-pitch/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk about copyright in Canada lately since we&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to perfect the updates the Conservatives are pitching to our outdated copyright legislation - so reading about Jeremy&amp;rsquo;s copyright woes in his recent post Perfect Pitch really struck a chord.
He discovered a page in The Sessions&amp;rsquo;s discussion form about perfect pitch had been removed from Google search results due to a copyright infringement accusation by a company that makes a product called Perfect Pitch - the page isn&amp;rsquo;t about the product and, in fact, barely mentions it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day Two</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 16:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Edenbee Social networking and carbon footprints by Clearleft. A Dao of Web Design Jeremy Keith says everyone must read this. It talks about giving up pixel perfect control of the display of your websites. Google social graph API Traces XFN and hCard references to connect your different profiles and find out who you are connected to. SCRUM Replacement for the waterfall development method. It&amp;rsquo;s agile. Recommended by Kelly Goto. Trulia Snapshot Data visualization by Stamen - using real estate in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links from An Event Apart 2008 - Day One</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 22:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-from-an-event-apart-2008-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Bobulate Can&amp;rsquo;t remember why it was mentioned but it is about IA and looks interesting. Wired Apparently half the people in the room read it. Jason used it as an example of how print can be very cool looking but the web is missing that pizzaz for individual articles. NY Times articles about Trolls Don&amp;rsquo;t feed the trolls. One of the trials of community managers. Flickr Colouring Contest Making lemonaid out or error messages as part of community management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site for my favorite client</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/new-site-for-my-favorite-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/new-site-for-my-favorite-client/</guid>
      <description>Just updated the look of Mum&amp;rsquo;s campaign website: Barb Hobson | A Strong Persistent Voice for Coquitlam-Maillardville. I changed everything without altering one line of HTML, man do I love CSS (IE6, I still hate you).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility Problem with Gilder/Levin Image Replacement Method</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 21:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/accessibility-problem-with-gilderlevin-image-replacement-method/</guid>
      <description>I have a friend who lives his life in low contrast. He is frequently the inspiration I need to go the extra mile and find an accessible solution to a programing quandary. A few weeks ago I had the good fortune to get to visit him and we cruised around the internet while drinking Rusty Nails so I could walk in his shoes for a bit.
His computer is set up to use one of Windows XP&amp;rsquo;s high contrast colour schemes and he also makes use of IE&amp;rsquo;s ability to override a website&amp;rsquo;s CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookstore wins a hubbie</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2008 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/bookstore-wins-a-hubbie/</guid>
      <description>Almost a year ago now the BCIT Bookstore let Web Services know that the e-commerce application they used to manage their online sales was upgrading and asked if we&amp;rsquo;d like to help skin the new site. The department was pretty busy at the time and my manager said we didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to help out but put them in contact with me so I could direct them to the style guide and technical guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping up</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/keeping-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 20:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/keeping-up/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;From your 77 subscriptions, over the last 30 days you read 809 items&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
 No wonder I don&amp;rsquo;t read any books any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally figure out what my problem is</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/finally-figure-out-what-my-problem-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 11:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/finally-figure-out-what-my-problem-is/</guid>
      <description>I read John Resig&amp;rsquo;s article Sub-Pixel Problems in CSS a few days ago and found it to very useful information.
And then today I had an &amp;ldquo;ah-ha&amp;rsquo; moment - this this is why I hate coding flexible horizontal navigation menus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Launches Social Graph API</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-launches-social-graph-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/google-launches-social-graph-api/</guid>
      <description>There were several speakers at WDN who spoke about open social networks, portability and consolidating friend information across applications. I found the talks interesting and then, while we were still at the conference, Google announced a Social Graph API aiming to do just what we&amp;rsquo;d been talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to check out from WDN08</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/links-to-check-out-from-wdn08/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Libraries Overview recommended by Cameron Adams as good comparison of major libraries Twine called Web 3.0 by Boris Mann dotMobi Mobile Web Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide by Brian Fling XHTML Mobile Profile Tutorial apparently if we know XHTML we know XHTML-MP, almost OpenID single sign on for the internet microformats.org/wiki/social-network-portability mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty OAuth.net mentioned by Brain Oberkirch&amp;rsquo;s talk on data portabilty DiSo Distributed Social networking applications development community kayak good example of potential use of portable data upcoming I have been instructed to get an account getsatisfaction people powered customer service foamee doesn&amp;rsquo;t require account creation, just uses your twitter info cabspotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing table based layouts</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/missing-table-based-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 18:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/missing-table-based-layouts/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s only one time where I ever really miss table based layouts: when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make a flexible horizontal navigation bar with centred links. Like this or this](http://louisgervais.com) website I made for a Vancouver gourmet catering company. chews on keyboard with frustration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I would live with dial up if it meant I could live here.</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/i-would-live-with-dial-up-if-it-meant-i-could-live-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/i-would-live-with-dial-up-if-it-meant-i-could-live-here/</guid>
      <description>One of my bestest friends lives in the middle of no where. High speed internet has not yet come to this island so I&amp;rsquo;m on dial up today, which is leading to interesting discoveries.
For example, IE6 loads images in the html before it loads background images from the CSS. Very interesting.
Also, turning off the images is not that easy. I wonder how true the assertion that people with dial up turn them off is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS bug in IE 6 with: .class a:hover element</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css-bug-in-ie-6-with-class-ahover-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/css-bug-in-ie-6-with-class-ahover-element/</guid>
      <description>This bug seems to apply to styling elements under a class or id within a link on hover. Stuff like .class a:hover span{} or #id a:hover strong{}. The solution is to define a property on the parent link .class a:hover{} that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been declared anywhere else in your CSS, like a text indent of 0 or something.
All the work for the solution was done by Tanfa, who wrote an article on IE Pure CSS Pop Ups Bug, I just thought it was worth mentioning that this bug can be generalized to more than the CSS menus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the switch</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-the-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 23:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/making-the-switch/</guid>
      <description>Macs have always struck me as more of a religion than an operating system. A family friend and I have a long history of a friendly Mac vs Windows rivalry. He&amp;rsquo;s the Mac evangelist and I was, well, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a Windows evangelist but I guess I played the part of a disbeliever.
At some point in 2004 he finally won the argument and I promised my next computer would be a Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming form guidelines</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/forming-form-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 16:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/forming-form-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Who knew web design could be so&amp;hellip; academic?
Since I got back from @media I&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work on a set of guidelines which ideally will one day guide the interaction and styling of all forms on the myriad of BCIT web applications though right now will only be applied to anything in the &amp;lsquo;public web&amp;rsquo; look and feel. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve done this much research since I finished university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media links to check out</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-links-to-check-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 02:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-links-to-check-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list consisting of all the websites and books recommended during the course of the conference that interested me enough to warrant writing down for later evaluation (including links to most of the presentations):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media: Day Two</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 02:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Today I got two free books, Jeremy signed Bullet Proof Ajax for me and I snagged an extra Microformats cheat sheet for Brandon. All in all a success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@media: Day One</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 10:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/media-day-one/</guid>
      <description>One day I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to make the same kind of contribution to the web design world that these speakers have. Trying to find a way to do that is as intimidating as the idea of writing a Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. How does one come up with new ideas?
The speakers have all been excellent so far. I always need a few days to process information though so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say at this point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADE/AMTECH Conference</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 01:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/cadeamtech-conference/</guid>
      <description>I was in Winnipeg speaking at the CADE/AMTECH Conference last week. The weather was beautiful and I saw an excellent hockey game in which the Manitoba Moose (the Vancouver Canucks&amp;rsquo; farm team) played spectacularly only to to be knocked out of the AHL playoffs in a very Canucks way (up 2-0 at the end of the first, lost 2-3 in OT).
As part of the Technology Enabled Knowledge (TEK) initiative at BCIT Danny Catt, one of the faculty, was sponsored to take a trip around South America and Antarctica studying local research and responses to sustainability and environmental issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious &#43; FireFox &#43; Snap Links</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/delicious-firefox-snap-links-just-the-way-i-like-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 15:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/delicious-firefox-snap-links-just-the-way-i-like-it/</guid>
      <description>I keep up on my favorite blogs and web comics by book marking them all in Firefox and then using the &amp;ldquo;open all in tabs&amp;rdquo; option that FireFox so nicely includes to open all the book marks at once. That way I can keep track of which ones I&amp;rsquo;ve read by closing them once I&amp;rsquo;m done :) Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s lazy I know.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to have access to my bookmarks when I&amp;rsquo;m away from my home computer (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t) so I jumped on the del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m presenting at a conference!</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 14:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/im-presenting-at-a-conference/</guid>
      <description>One of the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on at BCIT is Catt-Trax2. The website is for Danny Catt who is traveling through South America and Antarctica exploring conservation and sustainability issues and talking to the people in those regions working with those issues daily. He&amp;rsquo;s taking photos, video, and sound clips of this journey and blogging about his experiences. I helped architect the website and did some design and implementation work on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insecurity</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/insecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 21:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/insecurity/</guid>
      <description>All I did was copy the cgi file and change the file name and now it&amp;rsquo;s not encrypting the e-mails it sends any more.
Hm.
Edit: Yup, the problem was that I changed the name.
Edit 07-03-26: I&amp;rsquo;ve also discovered that cgi files are not encoded using windows text format so opening them in notepad and saving them again is enough to destroy all functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Border Collapse</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/border-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 20:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/border-collapse/</guid>
      <description>I am, for the most part, self taught when it comes to HTML and CSS. I&amp;rsquo;ve take a few courses to get a piece of paper that says I can do what I say I can do but learned very little from them.
I spotted this little CSS tidbit in a presenter&amp;rsquo;s code at the Web Directions North conference a few weeks ago and now I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if this is the sort of thing I missed out on by being self taught:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 01:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting a professional blog for a while now. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how there&amp;rsquo;s somethings you can tell complete strangers and there&amp;rsquo;s some things you can&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2 on MDN</title>
      <link>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/http2-on-mdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephaniehobson.ca/posts/http2-on-mdn/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on the Mozilla Marketing Engineering &amp;amp; Operations blog.
We enabled HTTP/2 on MDN&amp;rsquo;s CDN.
We didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything to optimize for HTTP/2, we just enabled it.
We&amp;rsquo;re seeing performance improvements.
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to get ready before you start using HTTP/2 While doing research to see if turning it on without doing any optimizations was a good idea I read things like:
 &amp;ldquo;It also means that all of those HTTP1 performance techniques are harmful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>