<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Taught on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/self-taught/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Taught on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 22:02:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/self-taught/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Abstract Sequential?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/why-abstract-sequential/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 22:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/why-abstract-sequential/</guid>
      <description>Short answer: it&amp;rsquo;s my thinking style :)
It means I enjoy theory, logic, precision and abstract thought and that I learn best through lecture, independent research, and following procedures. This means I love web design but makes my blog very, very boring.
It&amp;rsquo;s one of four learning styles as categorized by Dr. Anthony F. Gregorc. (I totally just Googled that). I first heard about my style from my teacher and friend Cheryl Atwater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Striving for excellence</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/striving-for-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/striving-for-excellence/</guid>
      <description>I just finished my first micoformatted page! When I was writing the information page for HOPE&amp;rsquo;s spring dinners I coded all the dinners as events and the organizers as hcards :) I did work with Brandon to re-do the BCIT Contacts application to use microformats but he did most of the coding on that project. This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve done it myself.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually tell anyone at HOPE that I&amp;rsquo;d done it that way since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t effect the way the page looks and I figure they&amp;rsquo;ll discover it for themselves if it&amp;rsquo;s useful to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something new today</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/something-new-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 15:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/something-new-today/</guid>
      <description>So apparently we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be encoding ampersands when we write them in the href part of anchor tags.
&amp;amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://stephaniehobson.ca/file.php » ?fire=hot&amp;amp;amp;amp;beer=foamy&amp;quot;&amp;amp;gt;link&amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Border Collapse</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/border-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 20:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/border-collapse/</guid>
      <description>I am, for the most part, self taught when it comes to HTML and CSS. I&amp;rsquo;ve take a few courses to get a piece of paper that says I can do what I say I can do but learned very little from them.
I spotted this little CSS tidbit in a presenter&amp;rsquo;s code at the Web Directions North conference a few weeks ago and now I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if this is the sort of thing I missed out on by being self taught:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>